(1985年10月26日星期六)
要不要去兜风?
How about a ride, mister?
詹妮弗
Jennifer.
天呀 看到你实在太好了!
Oh, man, are you a sight for sore eyes!
让我看看你
Let me look at you.
马丁 你表现得好像 我们一个礼拜没见面
Marty, you're acting like you haven't seen me in a week.
是没有
I haven't.
你还好吧 没什么事吧?
Are you okay? Is everything all right?
没事
Oh, yeah.
一切都很好
Everything's great.
马丁 你一定要跟我回去!
Marty! You've got to come back with me!
回哪?
Where?
回到未来
Back to the future.
等一下 你在干嘛?
Wait a minute. What are you doing, Doc?
我需要燃料
I need fuel.
(熔解先生：家用能源反应器)
走吧 快上车
Go ahead. Quick! Get in the car.
不行 我才刚回来
No, no, no. Look, Doc, I just got here, okay?
我和詹妮弗要开新车去兜风
Jennifer's here. We're gonna take the new truck for a spin.
带她一起去 这件事也跟她有关
Well, bring her along. This concerns her, too.
等一下 你在说什么?
Wait a minute, Doc. What are you talking about?
到底未来发生了什么事?
What happens to us in the future?
我们变成大混蛋了吗?
What, do we become assholes or something?
不是你们 你们都很好
No, no, no. You and Jennifer both turn out fine.
是你们的小孩
It's your kids, Marty.
你们的小孩需要帮忙
Something has got to be done about your kids.
最好退后一点 马路太短 我们没办法加速到88英里
Hey, Doc, we better back up. We don't have enough road to get up to 88.
马路? 我们去的地方不需要马路
Roads? Where we're going, we don't need roads.
马丁!
Say, Marty!
马丁 我那间汽车保养厂的
Marty! Marty, I wanted to show you these new matchbooks
火柴盒已经印好了 你来看
for my auto detailing I had printed up.
一部会飞的迪罗里安车?
A flying DeLorean?
到底是怎么回事?
What the hell is going on here?
《回到未来2》
那是什么东西?
What the hell was that?
出租车
Taxicab.
什么出租车 我们不是在飞吗
What do you mean a "taxicab"? I thought we were flying.
没错
Precisely.
博士 到底是怎么回事?
All right, Doc. What's going on, huh?
我们到底在何时、何地?
Where are we? When are we?
我们现在正朝 加州山谷镇方向前进
We're descending toward Hill Valley, California,
时间是2015年10月21日 星期三的下午4点29分
at 4:29 p.m. On Wednesday, October 21, 2015.
2015年?
2015?
难道说我们来到了未来
You mean we're in the future.
未来? 马丁 什么意思?
Future. Marty, what do you mean?
我们怎能来到未来?
How can we be in the future?
詹妮弗...
Jennifer...
我不知道该怎么解释 反正...
I don't know how to tell you this,
你现在坐在时光机中
but you're in a time machine.
这就是2015年?
And this is the year 2015?
2015年10月21日
October 21, 2015.
你没开玩笑吧
God, so, like, you weren't kidding.
我们能看到自己的未来
Marty, we can actually see our future.
博士 你说我们结婚了 对不对?
Doc, now, you said we were married, right?
是的...
Yeah...
婚礼盛大吗?
Yeah? Was it a big wedding?
马丁 我们能看到自己的婚礼
Marty, we're gonna be able to see our wedding.
哇! 我会看到自己的礼服
Wow. I'm gonna be able to see my wedding dress.
哇!
Wow.
我们住在哪里?
God, I wonder where we live.
一定是大房子 还有很多小孩
I bet it's a big house with lots of kids.
多少孩子...
How many kids...
博士 你在做什么?
Doc! What the hell are you doing?
放心
Relax, Marty.
那是安眠感应器
It's just a sleep-inducing alpha rhythm generator.
她问太多问题
She was asking too many questions,
人们对未来不能知道太多
and no one should know too much about their future.
如此一来 当她醒来时
This way when she wakes up,
只觉得是一场梦
she'll think it was all a dream.
那干嘛把她带来?
Then what did you bring her for?
我是迫于无奈
I had to do something.
当时她看到 不该看到的时光机
She saw the time machine. I couldn't just leave her there with that information.
放心 我的计划中她不是主角
Don't worry. She's not essential to my plan.
好吧 听你的
Well, you're the doc, Doc.
这里就是出口
Here's our exit.
(哥帝三世 山谷市市长欢迎您们)
(这里是居住的好地区)
首先 你先出去换衣服
First, you've gotta get out and change clothes.
现在? 雨那么大
Right now? It's pouring rain.
再等五秒钟
Wait five more seconds.
真准
Right on the tick.
太不可思议了
Amazing. Absolutely amazing.
可惜邮局就没有 气象局这么有效率
Too bad the post office isn't as efficient as the weather service.
(熔解工业)
我怕你认不出我来
Excuse the disguise, Marty,
所以伪装了一下
but I was afraid you wouldn't recognize me.
我到回春诊所
I went to a rejuvenation clinic
大修门面
and got an all-natural overhaul.
他们除皱、植发、换血
They took out some wrinkles, did a hair repair, changed the blood,
让我能再多活三、四十年
added a good 30 or 40 years to my life.
另外还换了脾脏和结肠 你看如何?
They also replaced my spleen and colon. What do you think?
你看起来年轻很多
You look great, Doc.
这就是未来
The future.
令人难以置信
Unbelievable.
我得去逛逛
I gotta check this out, Doc.
以后再说
All in good time, Marty.
现在时间紧迫
We're on a tight schedule here.
我知道我的未来应该很好
Tell me about my future. I mean, I know I make it big.
有没有成为 著名的摇滚乐歌星?
But what? Do I become, like, a rich rock star?
马丁 对未来不能知道太多
Please, Marty, no one should know too much about their own destiny.
好
Right. Right.
那我是不是很有钱?
I am rich, though, right?
马丁 别问了 把衣服脱掉
Marty, please, take off your shirt.
穿上夹克和鞋
Put on the jacket and the shoes.
我们有任务要去完成
Got a mission to accomplish.
完全按照预定时间
Precisely on schedule.
驱动式鞋带 棒!
Power laces. All right.
夹克太大了
This thing doesn't fit.
"调整尺寸 合身"
Size-adjusting fit.
把裤子口袋掏出来
Pull out your pants pockets.
所有的未来小孩 都是反穿裤子的
All kids in the future wear their pants inside out.
把帽子戴上
Put on this cap.
很好 现在你和你儿子完全一样
Perfect. You're the spitting image of your future son.
什么?
What?
帮我把詹妮弗搬到那里去
Help me move Jennifer over here.
到底是怎么回事?
So what's the deal?
抓住她的脚
Grab her feet.
好 然后呢?
All right. Okay, now what?
两分钟后你走进转角的 80年代咖啡店
In exactly two minutes, you go around the corner into the Cafe '80s.
80年代咖啡店?
Cafe '80s?
那是一间怀旧咖啡店 可惜生意不好
It's one of those nostalgia places, but not done very well.
进去叫一瓶百事可乐 这是五十块钱
Go in and order a Pepsi. Here's a 50.
然后等一个叫格里夫的人
Then wait for a guy named Griff.
好 等格里夫
Right. Griff. Right.
格里夫会问你:"今晚你去不去? "
Griff's going to ask you about tonight. Are you in or out?
告诉他你不去
Tell him you are out.
不管他说什么或发生什么事
Whatever he says, whatever happens,
都说不 说你没兴趣
say no, you're not interested.
好的
Okay.
然后离开 到这里来等我
Then leave, come back here and wait for me.
别和任何人讲话 别碰任何东西 什么都别做
Don't talk to anyone, don't touch anything, don't do anything,
别和任何人有互动
don't interact with anyone
最好什么也别看
and try not to look at anything.
我不懂 你不是说
I don't get it. I thought you said
这是关于我孩子的事吗
this had something to do with my kids.
这就是你儿子的事
Look what happens to your son.
那是我儿子?
My son?
(今日美国  青年偷窃被捕)
天呐 他长得和我一模一样
God, he looks just like me.
"在被捕两个钟头后
"Within two hours of his arrest, Martin McFly Jr
小马丁被判处
was tried, convicted and sentenced
坐牢十五年? "
to 15 years in a state penitentiary."
两个钟头内?
Within two hours?
未来的司法系统非常迅速
The justice system works swiftly in the future
因为他们废除了所有的律师
now that they've abolished all lawyers.
喔 这很严重
Oh, this is heavy.
更糟的在后面 下个礼拜你女儿
It gets worse. Next week, your daughter
试图劫狱去救他
attempts to break him out of jail,
结果被判做牢二十年
and she gets sent up for 20 years.
我女儿 我有女儿?
My daughter. Wait a minute. I have a daughter?
你儿子的事
You see? This one event starts a chain reaction
是你全家被毁的导火线
that completely destroys your entire family.
博士 这是明天的报纸
Hey, Doc, this date... This is tomorrow's newspaper.
没错 我曾到更前面
Precisely, I already went further ahead into time
去看有没有别的事发生
to see what else happens.
一路追查到此
I backtracked everything to this one event.
才在今天来这里
That's why we're here today,
阻止这件事的发生
to prevent this incident from ever happening.
糟糕 我晚了!
Damn! I'm late!
等等 你要到哪里去?
Wait a minute. Where you going now?
去截住小马丁
To intercept the real Marty Jr.
你好代替他 转角的80年代咖啡店
You're taking his place. Around the corner at the Cafe '80s.
记住对格里夫说"不"
Guy named Griff. Just say no!
可是我们不能把詹妮弗留在这里
Hey, what about Jennifer? We're not just gonna leave her here.
别担心 她不会有事的
Don't worry, she'll be safe.
只有几分钟
It'll just be for a few minutes.
马丁 小心格里夫
And, Marty, be careful around that Griff character.
他身上有加强体力的装置
He's got a few short circuits in his bionic implants.
这就是未来
The future.
(不准降落)
欢迎光临德州石油公司
Welcome to Texaco.
使用我们的机油 你的车子安全又可靠
You can trust your car to the system with the star.
检查机油、检查起落架
Checking oil. Checking landing gear.
(一路到底 大白鲨第十九集正在上映中)
鲨鱼仍旧不逼真
The shark still looks fake.
朋友们 我是哥帝三世
Hi, friends. Goldie Wilson III
威尔逊系统转换公司
for Wilson Hover Conversion Systems.
当我祖父做山谷镇市长时
You know, when my grandpa was mayor of Hill Valley,
他要担心交通问题
he had to worry about traffic problems.
但如今 你我都不用担心交通了
But now, you don't have to worry about traffic.
我能把你的旧车...
I'll hover-convert your old road car
转变为飞行车 只要39 999.95元
into a skyway flier for only $39,999.95.
过来看看我 哥帝三世
So come on down and see me, Goldie Wilson III,
我们总共有二十九家分店 请来和我们详谈
at any one of our 29 convenient locations.
记住 让旧车飞起来
Remember, keep 'em flying.
(熨斗... 古董电脑...)
(1950-2000运动年鉴)
或是要青椒炒肉面饼
Or fried meat pancake with green pepper.
是将辣番茄酱、鳄梨
It's got a hot salsa, avocados,
香菜 加在你所选择的豆子
cilantro mixed with your choice of beans,
鸡肉、牛肉或猪肉里
chicken, beef or pork.
服务生!
Waiter. Waiter.
要不要试试果馅卷
Would you like to try some rolls?
欢迎来到80年代咖啡店
Welcome to the Cafe '80s,
在美国任何时间都是早上 即使是在下午
where it's always morning in America, even in the afternoon.
今天的特餐是烤豆寿司
Our special today is mesquite-grilled sushi.
你一定要试人质特餐 是的
You must have the hostage special! Cajun style.
你一定要试人质特餐!
You must have the hostage special!
喂!
Hey, hey, hey, guys! Hey, hey, guys!
我只要瓶百事可乐
All I want is a Pepsi.
嗨 马丁!
Hey, McFly!
我常看到你
Yeah. I've seen you around.
你是老马丁的儿子 对不对?
You're Marty McFly's kid, aren't you?
贝夫?
Biff?
你是小马丁
You're Marty Jr.
真不容易呀
Tough break, kid.
和那个混蛋同名一定很痛苦
Must be rough being named after a complete butthead.
你是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
喂! 有人在家吗?
Hello? Hello? Anybody home?
嘿
Hey. Hey.
你猪脑啊!
Think, McFly, think!
你老爸是个笑柄?
Your old man? Mr. Loser?
什么?
What?
没错
That's right.
他是一个大笑柄
Loser with a capital "L."
我知道乔治不是...
Look, I happen to know George McFly is no longer a loser.
我不是在说乔治
No, I'm not talking about George McFly.
我是说他的儿子
I'm talking about his kid.
也就是你的老爸 马丁
Your old man, Marty McFly Sr.,
他潦倒一辈子
the man who took his life
天天冲厕所
and flushed it completely down the toilet.
我有吗?
I did?
我是说 他有吗?
I mean... I mean, he did?
爷爷
Hey, Gramps,
我告诉你要打两层蜡 不是一层!
I told you two coats of wax on my car, not just one!
上个礼拜我才打过第二层蜡
Hey, hey, I just put the second coat on last week.
你是闭着眼睛打吗?
Yeah? With your eyes closed?
你们俩是亲戚吗
Are you two related?
喂! 有人在家吗?
Hello? Hello? Anybody home?
你脑袋到哪儿去了 格里夫刚刚 不是叫我"爷爷"吗?
What do you think, Griff just calls me "Grandpa" for his health?
- 他就是格里夫? - 爷爷
- He's Griff? - Gramps!
真不懂为什么要付你钱?
What the hell am I paying you for?
孩子 替我向你奶奶问好
Hey, kid, say hello to your grandma for me.
爷爷 你出来
Get out here, Gramps.
你别急嘛!
Hey, take it easy!
马丁 你等着 哪儿都别去 下一个就是你!
And, McFly, don't go anywhere! You're next!
这是电动游戏机
This is a video game.
(西部枪手)
是我把它修好的
I got it working.
我爸爸教过我
My dad taught me about these.
那是西部枪手
It is Wild Gunman.
要怎么玩这个游戏?
How do you play this thing?
让我露两手给你们看
I'll show you, kid.
我可是一流的
I'm a crack shot at this.
(射击顶呱呱)
居然要用手去玩?
You mean you have to use your hands?
简直是婴儿的玩具
That's like a baby's toy.
婴儿玩具?
Baby's toy?
百事可乐 太好了
Pepsi Perfect.
- 糟糕 - 百事可乐
- Damn - Pepsi.
嗨 麦佛莱!
Hey, McFly!
我不是叫你在里面等我吗!
I thought I told you to stay in here!
格里夫 你们好吗?
Griff. Guys, how's it going?
- 麦佛莱 - 什么事?
- McFly! - Yeah?
- McFly! - What?
你的鞋带松了
Your shoe's unvelked.
今晚的事你决定了吗?
So, McFly, have you made a decision about tonight's opportunity?
格里夫 我实在不能确定
Yeah, Griff. You know, I was thinking about it. I'm not sure,
因为我认为
because I just think, you know,
这件事好像有点危险...
it might be a little bit dangerous, so...
麦佛莱 你怎么啦?
What's wrong, McFly?
没有阴囊吗?
You got no scrote?
他简直无能
He's a complete wimp.
你到底决定了没有? 要不要参加?
What's it gonna be, McFly? Are you in or out?
我还不能确定
I just... I'm not sure that I should.
因为我想和我爸爸商量一下
You know, because I think that I should discuss it with my father.
你爸爸? 你爸爸?
Your father? Your father?
答错了!
Wrong answer, McFly! You lose!
好 我参加 不管你说什么我都会做
Okay, Griff, I'll do it. I'll do it, buddy. Whatever you say.
待在这里别出声
Stay down and shut up.
你们俩继续骑 不准停下来
Keep pedaling, you two!
现在 让我听听正确的答案
Now, let's hear the right answer.
哇!
Well!
什么时候变狠啦?
Since when did you become the physical type?
答案是"不"
The answer's no, Griff.
"不"?
No?
没错 你是聋了还是听不懂?
Yeah. What are you, deaf and stupid?
我说"不"
I said no!
怎么啦? 胆小鬼?
What's wrong, McFly? Chicken?
你叫我什么?
What did you call me, Griff?
胆小鬼!
Chicken, McFly!
没人敢叫我...
Nobody calls me
胆小鬼
chicken.
- 好 来呀 - 你们看!
- All right, punk! - Hey, look!
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey, hey, hey.
等一等 小女孩!
Stop! Little girl, little girl. Stop.
等一下!
Hey. Look,
我想向你借盘旋板
I need to borrow your Hoverboard.
他在哪里?
Where is he?
给你
Here.
那里!
There!
他在盘旋板上
He's on a Hoverboard.
拿出盘旋板!
Get the boards!
去抓马丁!
Get McFly!
去抓他!
Get him!
在那里! 我们赶上他了!
Yeah! Yeah, we got him!
一切都那么熟悉
There's something very familiar about all this.
喂 你这个笨蛋!
Hey, McFly, you bojo!
板子不能在水上走!
Those boards don't work on water!
除非你有动力!
Unless you've got power!
钩起来!
Hook on!
(比特斗牛犬)
开始作战!
Batter up!
我的天!
Holy shit!
一群笨蛋
Buttheads.
(法院大楼)
"干燥程式开始"
Drying mode on.
"烘干夹克"
Jacket drying.
"你的夹克已干"
Your jacket is now dry.
嗨 小女孩 谢谢你
Hey, kid. Hey, little girl, thanks.
你留着 我有比特斗牛犬
Keep it. I got a Pit Bull now.
走吧
Come on. Let's go.
拯救钟塔!
Save the clock tower!
捐点钱
Hey, kid. Throw in 100 bucks, will you,
来拯救钟塔吧
and help save the clock tower.
- 我...对不起 不行 - 帮帮忙
- Sorry, no. - Come on, kid.
那是历史上重要的里程碑!
That's an important historical landmark!
以后吧
Look, some other time.
它在六十年前被闪电击中
Lightning struck that thing 60 years ago.
芝加哥小熊队得到世界冠军
Wait a minute. Cubs win World Series.
胜过迈阿密队?
Against Miami?
对 太出人意料了
Yeah, it's something, huh?
谁料得到? 这是一百比一呀!
Who would've thought? 100-1 shot!
真希望能回到过去开赛前
I wish I could go back to the beginning of the season,
好在小熊队身上下注
put some money on the Cubs.
我是说迈阿密...
I just meant that Miami...
你刚刚说什么?
What did you just say?
我说真希望能回到过去开赛前
I said I wish I could go back to the beginning of the season.
好在小熊队身上下注!
Put some money on the Cubbies!
这本书很有意思 外面还有封套(1950-2000运动年鉴)
Now this has an interesting feature. It has a dust jacket.
作用是保护书本
Books used to have these to protect the covers.
这当然是在防尘纸发明以前
Of course, that was before they had dust-repellent paper.
如果你喜欢灰尘
And if you're interested in dust,
我们有古雅的 1980年代的
we have a quaint little piece from the 1980s.
吸尘器
It's called a DustBuster.
- 我要发大财了 - 马丁!  在上面!
- I can't lose. - Marty! Marty! Up here!
博士 怎么样了?
Hey, Doc, what's going on?
你等着 我会停到你那里
Stand by. I'll park over there.
好的
Yeah, all right.
时间正好
Hey, right on time.
飞行的迪罗里安车
Flying DeLorean.
有三十年没见过了
I haven't seen one of those in 30 years.
对不起
Sorry. Excuse me. Sorry.
拜托 开车看路行不行!
Hey, I'm walking here! I'm walking here!
搞什么?
What the hell?
要开车就别吃镇定剂 讨厌!
Don't drive, trank, low-res scuzzball!
怎么会有两个他?
Two of them?
我让他不省人事
I left him in a suspended animation kennel.
就连爱因斯坦也搞不清状况!
Einstein never knew I was gone!
我的天 这里到底发生了什么事?
Marty! What in the name of Sir Isaac H. Newton happened here?
我儿子出现 搞得乱七八糟
Oh, yeah, Doc, listen, my kid showed up. All hell broke loose.
你儿子?
Your kid?
糟糕! 是安眠感应器 我好怕
Great Scott, the sleep inducer. I was afraid of this.
因为先用在詹妮弗身上
Because I used it on Jennifer,
所以剩下来的
there wasn't enough power left
不够让你儿子睡足一个钟头 糟糕!
to knock your son out for a full hour. Damn!
博士 你看!
Doc, Doc, Doc, look at this!
它在改变
It's changing.
(青年小马丁因偷窃被捕)
(阿飞党被拘留  盘旋板冲撞毁坏法院大楼)
我是被人陷害的!
I was framed!
对 这就对了!
Yes! Yes, of course!
由于盘旋板事件的发生
Because this Hoverboard incident has now occurred,
格里夫进了监牢
Griff now goes to jail.
你儿子就不会
Therefore, your son won't go with him tonight,
和他去偷东西
and that robbery will never take place.
如此一来 未来的历史...
Thus, history, future history,
被改写了 这就是证明!
has now been altered, and this is the proof!
我们成功了 虽然和我计划不同 管他的!
Marty, we've succeeded, not exactly as I planned, but no matter.
咱们去找詹妮弗然后回家!
Let's go get Jennifer and go home!
嗨 爱因斯坦
Hi, Einie. Hi, buddy.
这是什么?
What's this?
纪念品
It's a souvenir.
"五十年的运动统计资料"
"50 years of sports statistics."
根本就没有娱乐性
Hardly recreational reading material, Marty.
博士 把未来的资讯带回去
Well, hey, Doc, what's the harm
有什么不对?
in bringing back a little info on the future?
说不定还能赌上几把
You know, maybe we could place a couple bets.
马丁 我发明时光机不是为了赚钱!
Marty, I didn't invent the time machine for financial gain!
而是为了能够更透彻的观察人性
The intent here is to gain a clearer perception of humanity.
我们的所做、所为
Where we've been, where we're going,
陷阱与可能性、危险与圈套
the pitfalls and the possibilities, the perils and the promise.
甚至希望能找到探讨宇宙"为什么"的答案
Perhaps even an answer to that universal question, "Why?"
博士 我完全同意
Hey, Doc, I'm all for that.
但顺便赚点钱有什么不好?
What's wrong with making a few bucks on the side?
我要把它丢到垃圾桶去
I am going to put this in the trash.
我的天!
Great Scott!
詹妮弗住在山谷市 橡树街3793号
McFly, Jennifer Jane Parker, 3793 Oakhurst Street,
四十七岁
Hilldale, age 47.
四十七岁? 整容整得太棒了
Forty-seven? That's a hell of a good face-lift.
她们在做什么?
What the hell are they doing, Doc?
她们用指纹核对她的身份
They used her thumbprint to assess her ID.
既然指纹不变
Since her thumbprint never changes over the years,
她们就把她当成未来的詹妮弗
they simply assume she's the Jennifer of the future.
我们得去阻止她们
Well, we gotta stop them.
怎么开口? 告诉她们我们在做时光旅行吗?
What are we gonna say? That we're time travelers?
她们会把我们抓起来
They'd have us committed.
她没前科 把她送回家吧
She's clean. That means we take her home.
去山谷市?
Home? To Hilldale?
到那里天都黑了 只好如此
Lt'll be dark by the time we get out there.
她们要把她送回你未来的家!
That's it. They're taking her home to your future home!
我们在她们之后到达
We'll arrive shortly thereafter,
找到她 就回到1985年
get her out of there and go back to 1985.
那么我可以看到我住在哪里?
You mean I'm gonna see where I live?
和我老了是什么样子?
I'm gonna see myself as an old man?
不行 那会引起...我的天!
No, no, no, Marty. That could result in... Great Scott!
詹妮弗一定会遇到 未来的自己!
Jennifer could conceivably encounter her future self!
后果可能会不可收拾!
The consequences of that could be disastrous!
博士 你在说什么?
Doc, what do you mean?
我预见两种可能性
I foresee two possibilities.
第一 看到三十年后的自己
One, coming face to face with herself 30 years older
会让她吓昏过去
would put her into shock, and she'd simply pass out,
或是第二 会遭遇时间冲突
or two, the encounter could create a time paradox,
而导致破坏时空的
the results of which could cause a chain reaction that would unravel
连锁反应
the very fabric of the space-time continuum
进而摧毁整个宇宙!
and destroy the entire universe!
这是最坏的假设
Granted, that's a worst-case scenario.
毁灭也许是局部性
The destruction might, in fact, be very localized,
只限于我们自己的银河系
limited to merely our own galaxy.
那叫我放心不少
Well, that's a relief.
走吧 希望我们能 在她找到自己之前找到她
Let's go. I sure hope we find Jennifer before she finds herself.
(C25航线有偏移)
航线堵塞了 要开很久才能到
The skyway's jammed. It's gonna take us forever to get there.
不准带它走
And this stays here.
我发明时光机 不是用来赌博的
I didn't invent the time machine to win at gambling.
是用它来穿梭时光岁月的!
I invented a time machine to travel through time!
我知道 我知道 我知道
I know. I know. I know, Doc.
布朗博士居然发明了时光机
So, Doc Brown invented a time machine.
(山谷警察)
(山谷市)
山谷市
Hilldale.
一个镇定剂、流氓滋生的地方
Nothing but a breeding ground for tranks, lobos and zipheads.
真该把这地方拆掉
Yeah, they ought to tear this whole place down.
詹妮弗 欢迎回家
Welcome home, Jennifer.
- 你没事吧? - 没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
你体内有点镇定剂 但应该能够走路
You got a little tranked, but I think you can walk.
夫人 你应该重新调整程式
Ma'am, you should reprogram.
进门不开灯很危险
It's dangerous to enter without lights on.
开灯?
Lights on?
是的 听着
Yes. Now, look.
你休息一下就没问题了
Just take it easy and you'll be fine.
将来要小心
And be careful in the future.
将来?
The future?
麦佛莱太太 祝你有个愉快的一天
Have a nice day, Mrs. McFly.
全天播出美丽的视野
Broadcasting beautiful views 24 hours a day,
你正在收看风景频道
you're tuned to the Scenery Channel.
我是在未来
I'm in the future.
(爱的礼拜堂)
我居然在爱的礼拜堂结婚
I get married in the Chapel O Love?
妈 是你吗?
Mom? Mom, is that you?
我得赶快离开这里!
I gotta get out of here!
妈!
Mom!
妈 是你吗?
Mom? Mom, is that you?
奶奶!
Grandma Lorraine!
甜心!
Sweetheart!
嗨 嗨!
Hi! Hi!
爷爷怎么了?
What happened to Grandpa?
他背痛的毛病又犯了
Oh, he threw his back out again.
爷爷的甜心好不好?
How's Granddad's little pumpkin?
爷爷 你是怎么搞的? 他是怎么搞的?
How did you do that? How did he do that?
打高尔夫球不小心弄到的
Oh, out on the golf course.
你爸妈回来了吗?
Are your folks home yet?
我带比萨饼来请大家吃
I brought pizza for everyone.
谁会吃嘛?
Oh, who's going to eat all that?
我会
Oh, I will.
交通真挤!
Damn this traffic!
詹妮弗通常是这时候到家的
Jennifer, that is Old Jennifer, usually gets home around now.
希望我们没太迟
I hope we're not too late.
博士 怎么啦?
What is it? What's the matter, Doc?
我好像看到出租车
For a moment, I thought I saw a taxi in my rear display.
貌似在跟踪我们 天呀
I thought it was following us. Weird.
这扇窗子怎么仍是破的
I can't believe this window's still broken.
当修理工叫爸爸胆小鬼时
Well, when the scenescreen repairman called Daddy a chicken,
爸爸就把他丢出去
Daddy threw him out of the house.
现在再也找不到人来修了
Now, we can't get anybody to fix it.
你看坏成这个样子
Oh, look how worn out this is.
马琳 你爸爸最大的毛病就是
Your father's biggest problem, Marlene,
别人一叫他胆小鬼
is that he loses all self-control
他就控制不住自己
when someone calls him chicken.
乔治 我们听他说过多少次?
How many times have we heard it, George?
"妈 我不能让人以为我是胆小鬼"
"Mom, I can't let them think I'm chicken."
"不能让人以为我是胆小鬼"
"Can't let them think I'm chicken."
你一点也没错!
You're right. Well, you're right!
三十年前
About 30 years ago,
你爸爸为了证明他不是胆小鬼
your father tried to prove he wasn't chicken,
结果发生那次车祸
and he ended up in an automobile accident.
就是和劳斯莱斯相撞那一次?
Oh, you mean with the Rolls-Royce?
车祸?
Automobile accident.
爱因斯坦 我们去找詹妮弗
All right, Einie, let's find Jennifer.
真不敢相信 我住在山谷市
I don't believe it. I live in Hilldale?
- 挺不错的嘛! - 走了
- This is great! - Way to go, McFly.
马丁 你留在这里换衣服
Marty, stay here. Just change clothes.
需要你时我会叫你的
If I need you, I'll holler.
我想去看我的房子
Come on, Doc, I wanna check out my house.
你可能会碰到未来的自己
We can't risk you running into your older self.
爱因斯坦 我们走
Come on, Einie, let's go.
詹妮弗在哪里? 詹妮弗在哪里?
Where's Jennifer? Where's Jennifer?
山谷市
Hilldale.
太棒了
This is bitching.
一百七十四块五毛钱
One, seven, four point five zero.
一共是一百七十四块五毛钱
That will be $174.50.
给你
Here.
小心点 这里很不安全
I'd be careful, old timer. This is a rough neighborhood.
- 收据呢? - 在这里
- Where's my receipt? - Right here. Here it is.
有没有小费?
Hello. Hello. How about a tip?
(垃圾回收站)
就是那个车祸
That accident caused a chain reaction
毁了他这一生
that sent Marty's life straight down the tubes.
否则你爸爸
If not for that accident, your father's life
会很不同
would have turned out very differently.
没有劳斯莱斯的车主 要求他赔偿损失
The man in the Rolls-Royce wouldn't have pressed charges,
马丁就不会伤了手
Marty wouldn't have broken his hand,
而放弃他的音乐
and he wouldn't have given up on his music,
从此以后生活在自怨自艾之中
and he wouldn't have spent all those years feeling sorry for himself.
妈 裤子很好看
Hey, Mom, nice pants.
你妈会和他结婚主要的原因
I think the real reason your mother married him was because
- "妈"? - 是因为她可怜你爸爸
- "Mom"? - she felt sorry for him.
她真是个好孩子
Such a sweet girl.
- 关掉美术画面 - 也许她应该...
- Art off. - I think maybe she deserves...
我要18、24、63、109、87 和气象频道
Okay, I want channels 18, 24, 63, 109, 87 and the Weather Channel.
气象频道 带给你
The Weather Channel, bringing you
每天24小时的气象资讯
the world's weather 24 hours a day.
天前还是老样子...
Weather conditions remain the same...
所有注册整容医生...
All board-certified implant surgeons...
稍微回暖...
With a minor warm front...
马丁 欢迎回家
Welcome home, Marty.
嗨! 爸爸回家了
Hey, hey, hey. Dad's home.
没错 我回家了 爸爸回家了
That's right. He's home. Dad's home.
贵族的庄园 哈罗
Lord of the manor. Hello. Hello.
国王的城堡
King of the castle.
哈罗
Hello.
搞什么?
What the hell is this?
生活程式开始
Lithium mode on.
好多了 这些小鬼
Yeah. That's better. Damned kids.
嗨 儿子
Hey, Son.
怎么换成看小电视?
Watching a little TV for a change?
这是什...
Son of a...
比萨饼 饿死了 (必胜客)
Hey, pizza. I'm hungry.
别急
All right. Just wait your turn.
热好的时候
Grandma, when it's ready,
能不能塞到我嘴里?
could you just shove it in my mouth?
你的玩笑一点也不好笑
Don't you be a smartass.
太好了 这是残酷频道
Oh, great! The Atrocity Channel.
水合程度四
Hydrate level 4, please.
好了吗?
Is it ready?
好了
Here you go.
哇! 妈妈
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
你的水合比萨饼真好吃
Mom, you sure can hydrate a pizza.
对不起 怎么回事?
I'm sorry. I missed that whole thing.
我是担心詹妮弗 她怎么还没回家?
Well, I'm just worried about Jennifer. Why isn't she home yet?
我不知道詹妮弗到哪去了
I'm not sure where Jennifer is, Mom.
她几个钟头前就应该到家的
She should have been home hours ago.
最近我也不知道她的行踪
I'm having a hard time keeping track of her these days.
来点水果? 水果 谢谢
Hey, fruit. Fruit, please. Thank you.
她好像又在闹情绪
She's in one of those moods, I guess. I don't know.
你和詹妮弗之间出问题了吗?
Aren't you and Jennifer getting along?
我们很好
Oh, yeah. Great, Mom.
就像年轻时候一样
We're more like a couple of teenagers, you know.
(电话)
爸爸 是尼德的电话
Dad, telephone. It's Needles.
爸爸 找你的
Dad, it's for you.
好 我到书房去接
All right. Well, I'll take that in the den. Excuse me.
收回!
Retract.
喂 我在这里
Hello. I'm in here, please.
嗨 马丁 近来如何?
Hey, the big M. How's it hanging, McFly?
嗨 尼德
Hey, Needles.
尼德?
Needles?
你有没有看我的企划书?
So, did you take look at that little business proposal of mine?
我不知道
I don't know, Needles.
你怕什么?
What are you afraid of?
如果成功了 就能解决你的财务困难
If this thing works, it'll solve all your financial problems.
如果不成 我会被解雇
And if it doesn't work, Needles, I could get fired.
这是非法的 说不定富士通正在监视
It's illegal. I mean, what if the Jits is monitoring, huh?
他不会发现的
The Jits will never find out.
喔 天呀
Oh, God.
别这样嘛! 把卡放在卡槽里 其余由我来处理
Come on. Stick your card in the slot, and I'll handle it.
除非你要大家都认为 你是个胆小鬼
Unless you want everyone in the division to think you're chicken.
没人叫我胆小鬼
Nobody calls me chicken, Needles.
没人!
Nobody!
好
All right.
证明呀
Prove it.
好
All right.
尼德 你赢了
All right, Needles.
这是我的卡 正在扫瞄 你满意了吧
Here's my card. Scan it. I'm in.
谢谢你 马丁 明天工厂见
Thanks, McFly. I'll see you at the plant tomorrow.
(谢谢使用美国电报电话)
胆小鬼
Chicken.
马丁!
McFly!
伊藤富士通  富士通先生 晚安
我在监视 你刚刚所做的扫瞄
McFly, I was monitoring that scan you just interfaced.
你被解雇了!
You are terminated!
解雇 不要!
Terminated. No!
那不是我的错 是尼德的错
No! It wasn't my fault, sir. It was Needles.
尼德是幕后人
Needles was behind the whole thing.
但是你和他合作
And you cooperated.
- 不 我没有 这是例行程序. - 这是违法的
- No, I didn't. It was a sting operation. - It was illegal.
我在骗他
I was setting him up.
看我的传真!
And you knew. McFly, read my fax!
求求你不要开除我 不要这样做 我被开除了
No! Please, no. I cannot be fired. I'm fired.
(你被开除了)
这太严重了
Oh, this is heavy.
我要怎么对詹妮弗说?
What am I going to tell Jennifer?
詹妮弗 詹妮弗
Jennifer. Jennifer.
博士 我真高兴看到你
Oh, Doc, am I glad to see you.
从前门出去 我在那里等你
Go out the front door. I'll meet you there.
没有门把 门打不开
But it doesn't open. There's no doorknob.
用拇指按金属板
Press your thumb to the plate.
什么金属板?
What plate?
这个传真是什么意思?
Marty, what does this fax mean?
这是公司开的玩笑 是一种玩笑传真
Oh, Mom, it's a joke, an office joke. Kind of a joke fax.
马丁 我听到你在叫
Marty, I heard you yelling.
妈 你别紧张
Mom, Mom, Mom, calm down.
我没有叫 尼德和我在闹着玩
I wasn't yelling. Needles and I were just kind of joking.
詹妮弗 欢迎回家
Welcome home, Jennifer.
马丁 你失业了?
Marty, have you lost your job?
失业 妈 你想到那里去了...
Lost my job, Mom? Get out of town. Look, you know...
- 我这么年轻! - 我这么老!
- I'm young! - I'm old!
马丁 马丁!
Marty! Marty!
马丁 快来!
Marty, come quick! Quick!
她见到未来的自己后
She encountered her older self
昏倒了 就如我所预测的
and went into shock, just as I predicted.
她不会有事的
She'll be fine.
快把她送回1985年
Let's get her back to 1985,
然后就毁灭这部时光机
and then I'm gonna destroy the time machine.
毁灭它?
Destroy it?
那怎么去洞察人性
What about that stuff about humanity,
和找出"为什么"的解答?
where we're going and why?
冒的危险太大了
The risks are just too great, as this incident proves.
我必须负起这个责任
And I was behaving responsibly.
你能想象
You can imagine the danger
时光机落入坏人之手 的后果会怎样?
if the time machine were to fall into the wrong hands.
我唯一的遗憾 是没法
My only regret is that I'll never get a chance
去我最喜欢的年代
to visit my favorite historical era,
旧西部
the Old West.
但时光旅行实在太危险了
But time traveling is just too dangerous.
我还是专心研究
Better that I devote myself to studying
宇宙中其他难解的迷
the other great mystery of the universe,
就是女人
women.
马丁、爱因斯坦 准备暂时时间转移
Marty, Einie, brace yourselves for temporal displacement.
我们成功了吗?
Did we make it?
我们回去了没有?
Are we back?
我们回来了
We're back.
先把她放在吊椅上
Let's put her in the swing.
然后我送你回家 等会儿
Then I'll take you home, and you can come back
你再开车来叫醒她
in your truck and wake her.
等她醒过来 天又这么晚
When she awakens here in her own house and it's dark,
你就比较容易说服她 那是一场梦
you should be able to convince her that it was all a dream.
等等 我们就这样
Wait a minute. We're just gonna
把她留在门廊上?
leave her here on the porch?
迷惘会帮你说服她 这是一场梦
The disorientation will help convince her that it was all a dream.
她还会睡多久?
How long do you think she's gonna be out?
不清楚 她受到的打击不小
I'm not quite sure. She received quite a shock.
可能几分钟
Could be for a few minutes.
也可能几小时
Most probably, a couple of hours.
你最好把嗅盐带来
You better bring smelling salts back with you.
听你的
You're the doc, Doc.
来 爱因斯坦 我们走
All right. Come on. Let's go, Einie.
放心 她不会有事的
Don't worry. She'll be fine.
窗上怎么会有铁条
I don't remember bars being on these windows.
(里昂地产)
如果要找我 我会在实验室里拆这玩意
If you need me, I'll be back at my lab dismantling this thing.
好
Right.
怎么回事?
What the hell?
嘿 等等
Hey. Hey, wait. Wait a minute.
你在我房间干什么?
What are you doing in my room?
妈 强暴!
Help! Rape! Mom!
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
爸 救命!
Dad, help!
混蛋 不准动!
Freeze, sucker!
- 他爬到我身上 - 没事的 我不是来找麻烦的
- He jumped me! - Hey, it's okay. I don't want any trouble.
他破窗而入!
He came through the window!
你这个小混混 你麻烦大了
You got trouble now, you piece of trash.
你找我女儿干嘛?
What are you doing in here with my daughter?
我进错了房子
Hey, listen, I'm just in the wrong house.
你是进错了房子 你这个混...
You got that right, you little son of a...
我做错了
Hey, look, I made a mistake.
是的 你是大错特错!
Damn right you made a mistake!
宰了他!
Kill him!
我要把你碎尸万段!
I'm gonna tear your ass up!
跑呀! 有本事就跑!
That's right. You keep running, sucker!
告诉那个房地产公司
And you tell that realty company
我不会卖房子的
that I ain't selling! You hear?
他们吓不了我们!
We ain't gonna be terrorized!
一定是搞错年代了
This has gotta be the wrong year.
1985年?
1985?
不可能
It can't be.
把报纸放下来
Drop it.
你就是偷报纸的小混蛋
So you're the son of a bitch who's been stealing my newspapers.
史特兰老师
Mr. Strickland.
史特兰老师 是我 我是马丁
Mr. Strickland. It's me, sir. It's Marty.
谁?
Who?
马丁
It's Marty McFly. Marty McFly.
是你学校的学生
Don't you know me, sir? From school, sir.
我从没看过你
I've never seen you before in my life,
你看来就是个懒鬼
but you look to me like a slacker.
没错 我爱偷懒
Yeah, that's right. That's right. I am a slacker.
记得吗? 上星期你还罚过我
Don't you remember? You gave me detention last week.
上星期? 学校六年前就被烧毁了
Last week? The school burned down six years ago.
限你三分钟
Now, you got exactly three seconds
离开我家 否则让你生不如死
to get off my porch with your nuts intact.
- 一 - 不要 史特兰老师
- One. - Please, Mr. Strickland,
我只想知道到底出了什么事
I just want to know what the hell's going on here.
二
Two.
喂 姓史的!
Hey, Strickland!
赏你们子弹吃!
Eat lead, slackers!
(欢迎光临山谷市 居家的好地方)
走路看路行不行
Watch where you're going, crazy drunk pedestrian.
瑞德
Red.
(贝夫极乐天堂  贝夫添南博物馆)
(贝夫的家)
(地狱奇景)
(坦尼娅异国性爱  骨头)
(有毒工业废料开垦区)
(赌场)
各位先生女士们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎来到贝夫添南博物馆
welcome to the Biff Tannen Museum.
他是个 献身于山谷镇的居民
Dedicated to Hill Valley's number one citizen
也是美国的民间英雄
and America's greatest living folk hero,
他就是独一无二的贝夫
the one and only Biff Tannen.
我们都听过他的传奇 但没有切身体会
Of course, we've all heard the legend, but who is the man?
在馆内你将得知
Inside, you will learn
这位幸运儿是如何成为
how Biff Tannen became one of the richest
美国最有钱有势的人
and most powerful men in America.
以及这个家族的辉煌历史
Learn the amazing history of the Tannen family,
他祖父就是疯狗布夫
starting with his great-grandfather, Buford "Mad Dog" Tannen,
西部第一快枪手
fastest gun in the West.
贝夫出生卑微
See Biff's humble beginnings
当他二十一岁生日时
and how a trip to the racetrack
到赛马场赢得百万的财富
on his 21 st birthday made him a millionaire overnight.
(山谷镇居民赛马场大获全胜)
手气好得难以置信
Share in the excitement of a fabulous winning streak
他因此获得"世界最幸运的人"的绰号
that earned him the nickname "The Luckiest Man on Earth."
更可得知他如何利用好运气
Learn how Biff parlayed that lucky winning streak
建立起 贝夫可这个庞大的王国
into the vast empire called Biffco.
以及他如何在1979年 成功的游说赌博合法化
Discover how in 1979, Biff successfully lobbied to legalize gambling
并将山谷镇 快倒塌的法院大楼
and turned Hill Valley's dilapidated courthouse
转变成美丽的赌场旅馆
into a beautiful casino hotel.
我只想说一件事: 天佑美国!
I just want to say one thing. God bless America!
见一见他热爱过的女人
Meet the women who shared in his passion
和他寻觅多时的真爱
as he searched for true love,
并重新体验 贝夫最快乐的一刻
and relive Biff's happiest moment
在1973年他终于和相爱多年的
as, in 1973, he realized his life-long romantic dream
高中恋人洛莲结婚
by marrying his high school sweetheart, Lorraine Baines McFly.
结婚的感觉怎么样?
How's it feel, Mr. Tannen?
事不过三
Third time's the charm.
不 不!
No! No!
你和我们到楼上去
Hey, you're coming with us upstairs.
让我走!
Let me go.
我们可以来硬的 也可以来软的
Look, sonny, we can do this the easy way or the hard way.
来软的吧
The easy way.
妈? 妈 是你吗?
Mom? Mom, is that you?
马丁 你别紧张
Just relax, Marty.
你睡了将近两个钟头
You've been asleep for almost two hours.
我做了一个很恐怖的梦
I had a horrible nightmare. It was terrible.
别怕 这里非常安全
Well, you're safe and sound now,
你现在是在二十七楼的家里
back on the good old 27th floor.
二十七楼!
Twenty-seventh floor!
妈 那不可能是你
Mom? Mom, that can't be you.
是我 马丁 你没事吧?
Well, yes, it's me, Marty. Are you all right?
我很好 只是你怎么会...
I'm fine. I'm fine. It's just that you're so... You're so
那么大
big.
一切都会好转的 你饿不饿?
Oh. Everything's gonna be fine, Marty. Are you hungry?
我可以叫客房服务送吃的来
I can call room service.
客房服务?
Room service?
洛莲!
Lorraine!
糟糕 是你父亲
Oh, my God. It's your father.
我父亲?
My father?
你这个小混蛋 你现在应该在瑞士
You're supposed to be in Switzerland, you little son of a bitch!
爸?
My father!
又被寄宿学校踢出来了吗?
Did you get kicked out of another boarding school?
他妈的 洛莲 为你这个不争气的儿子
Damn it, Lorraine. Do you know how much perfectly good dough
我花了多少钱?
I've blown on this no-good kid of yours, huh?
三个全不争气?
On all three of them?
你吵什么 又不是供不起
What the hell do you care? We can afford it.
至少用那些钱
The least we can do with all that money
让我们的儿女过好点
is provide a better life for our children.
等一下
Hold on one second.
我先说清楚 马丁是你的儿子 不是我的
Let's get this straight. Marty is your kid, not mine.
就算用全世界的钱供他
And all the money in the world
还是没用
wouldn't do jack shit for that lazy bum.
你别说了
Stop it, Biff. Just stop it.
看看他 根本就是个笨蛋 和他老爸一样
Look at him. He's a butthead, just like his old man was.
不准你那样说乔治
Don't you dare speak that way about George.
你连他的一半都不如
You're not even half the man he was.
你这个猪狗不如的东西
You son of a bitch! Hey.
永远是那么暴躁
Always the little hothead, huh?
想捅我几下吗?
You wanna take a poke at me?
该死 我受够了 我要离开
Damn it, Biff. That's it. I'm leaving.
那就走呀 但想清楚
So go ahead. But think about this, Lorraine!
谁替你付那些置装费
Who's gonna pay for all your clothes, huh?
还有珠宝和酒?
And your jewelry and your liquor?
谁替你付美容整形费?
Who's gonna pay for your cosmetic surgery, Lorraine?
是你要我弄得这么大的
You were the one who wanted me to get these things.
你想要就还给你
If you want them back, you can have them.
听好了 你要是敢走出这扇门
Look, Lorraine. You walk out that door,
我不但不供你 也不供你那些孩子们
and I won't only cut off you. I'll cut off your kids.
你不会的
You wouldn't.
是吗?
Wouldn't I?
首先 我会取消
First your daughter, Linda.
你女儿琳达的信用卡
I'll cancel all her credit cards.
让她自己去和银行交涉欠款
She can settle her debts with the bank all by herself.
你那白痴儿子大卫 我要撤回他的假释
Your idiot son, Dave. I'll get his probation revoked.
至于马丁
And as for Marty.
也许你喜欢看到 他们三个和你弟弟乔伊一样
Well, maybe you'd like to have all three of your kids behind bars,
全都关到牢里去
just like your brother Joey.
在监狱里来个全家大团圆
One big, happy, jailbird family.
好了 你赢 我留下来
All right, Biff. You win. I'll stay.
至于你 一小时内你最好消失
As for you, I'll be back up here in an hour, so you better not be.
他没错 是我错了
He was right, and I was wrong.
妈!
Mom!
你说什么
Mom, what are you saying?
你怎么能替他辩护?
You're actually defending him.
是我自找的 他是我丈夫
I had it coming. He's my husband,
而且他照顾我们
and he takes care of all of us,
他应该得到我们的尊敬
and he deserves our respect.
尊敬?
Respect?
你的丈夫! 他怎么会是你的丈夫?
Your husband! How could he be your husband?
你怎么会离开爸爸嫁给他?
How could you leave Dad for him?
离开爸爸?
Leave Dad?
马丁 你没事吧?
Marty, are you feeling all right?
不 我不好!
No. No, I'm not feeling all right!
我一点也不知道 这里发生了什么事
I don't understand one damn thing that's going on around here,
为什么没人告诉我呢
and why nobody can give me a simple, straight answer.
你的头一定被打得很厉害
Oh, they must have hit you over the head hard this time.
妈 我只想知道一件事
Mom, I just want to know one thing.
我的爸爸乔治在哪里?
Where's my father? Where's George McFly?
乔治...你的爸爸
Marty, George, your father
十二年来一直在同一个地方
is in the same place he's been for the past 12 years.
就是橡园公墓内
Oak Park Cemetery.
(永恒的记忆  乔治麦佛莱之墓)
不
No.
不可能发生的
No! This can't be happening!
1973年3月15日?
"March 15, 1973."
不 天啊 不
No! Please, God, no!
喔 上帝!
No, please, God. Please, God, no.
这不可能发生
This can't be happening.
不可能的...
This can't be...
恐怕这一切都是真的
I'm afraid it is happening, Marty. All of it.
博士!
Doc!
当我知道你父亲的事时
When I learned about your father,
就猜你会到这里来
I figured you'd come here.
那你知道他出了什么事吗?
Then you know what happened to him?
你知道1973年3月15日发生什么事?
Do you know what happened March 15, 1973?
是的 我知道
Yes, Marty. I know.
我到图书馆
I went to the public library
想把事情弄清楚
to try to make sense out of all the madness.
图书馆被封闭
The place was boarded up, shut down,
只好闯进去借报纸看
so I broke in and borrowed some newspapers.
我搞不懂
I don't get it, Doc.
这些事怎么会发生的?
I mean, how can all this be happening?
我们像生活在地狱里
It's like we're in hell or something.
不 这里是山谷镇 不过地狱也不会差到哪里去
No, it's Hill Valley. Although, I can't imagine hell being much worse.
爱因斯坦 对不起
Oh, Einie. I'm sorry, boy.
实验室乱七八糟
The lab is an awful, awful, awful, awful mess.
来 乖狗
Attaboy.
显然的 时空已经大乱
Obviously, the time continuum has been disrupted,
由于两个时空的交替
creating this new temporal event sequence
而导致这种暂时的结果
resulting in this alternate reality.
请你说白一点
English, Doc.
让我画给你看
Here, here, here. Let me illustrate.
假设这条线代表时间
Imagine that this line represents time.
这里是现在1985年 这是未来 这是过去
Here's the present, 1985, the future and the past.
在这一点之前 也就是过去的某个时间
Prior to this point in time, somewhere in the past,
时间线被扭曲
the timeline skewed into this tangent
而创造出另一个1985年
creating an alternate 1985.
对你、我和爱因斯坦 这是个扭曲的时空
Alternate to you, me and Einstein,
但对别人则是真实的
but reality for everyone else.
认得这个吗?
Recognize this?
这是装运动年鉴的袋子
It's the bag the sports book came in.
因为收据还在里面
I know, because the receipt was still inside.
我在时光机里找到的 另外还有这个东西
I found them in the time machine along with this.
这是贝夫的拐杖头
It's the top of Biff's cane.
我是指未来的老贝夫
I mean, Old Biff from the future.
对 如果它在时光机中
Correct. It was in the time machine
那就表示贝夫 和年鉴也曾待在时光机里
because Biff was in the time machine with the sports almanac.
我的天
Holy shit.
当我们在未来时
You see, while we were in the future,
贝夫拿走年鉴
Biff got the sports book,
偷了时光机 回到过去
stole the time machine, went back in time,
然后把书给了自己
and gave the book to himself at some point in the past.
你看 证明就在这里
Look. It says right here
贝夫在1958年
that Biff made his first million
赢得一百万元
betting on a horse race in 1958.
他并不是运气好
He wasn't just lucky.
是因为他有年鉴
He knew because he had all the race results in the sports almanac.
他是这样赚得全部的财富
That's how he made his entire fortune.
用放大镜看他的口袋
Look at his pocket with a magnifying glass.
就是那本年鉴
The almanac.
混蛋 居然偷我的主意
Son of a bitch stole my idea.
他一定听我讲...
He must have been listening when I...
我错了 整件事都是我的错
It's my fault. The whole thing is my fault.
假如当初不买那本书
If I hadn't bought that damn book,
什么事也不会发生
none of this would have ever happened.
事情已经过去
Well, it's all in the past.
不 是未来?
You mean the future?
不管怎样 它证明
Whatever. It demonstrates precisely
时光机误用的可怕后果
how time travel can be misused
等把这些事情改正后
and why the time machine must be destroyed
一定要把时光机毁掉
after we straighten all of this out.
对 我们回到未来
Right. So we go back to the future,
阻止贝夫偷时光机
and we stop Biff from stealing the time machine.
不行 如果从这里
We can't, because if we travel
出发去未来的话
into the future from this point in time,
那会进入这个时空的未来
it will be the future of this reality,
在这里 贝夫是个贪污且有势力的人
in which Biff is corrupt and powerful
并和你妈妈结婚 而且...
and married to your mother
这也发生在我身上
and in which this has happened to me.
(疯子发明家被判神精错乱)
若要改变现在必须回到过去
No. Our only chance to repair the present is in the past
回到时间线被扭曲之前
at the point where the timeline skewed into this tangent.
为了要恢复宇宙秩序
In order to put the universe back as we remember it
回到真正的时空
and get back to our reality,
我们必须找到真正的日期
we have to find out the exact date
还有特定的环境
and the specific circumstances
在何时、何地
of how, where and when Young Biff
小贝夫如何拿到那本运动年鉴
got his hands on that sports almanac.
我去问他
I'll ask him.
防弹衣! 天呀
Bulletproof vest! Great flick! Great frigging flick!
这家伙真聪明!
The guy is brilliant.
搞什么...
Hey, what the hell's going...
你到这里干什么?
Hey! What the hell are you doing in here?
贝夫 宴会结束了
Party's over, Biff.
小姐们 对不起
Sorry, ladies.
你怎么会通过我的警卫?
How did you get past my security downstairs?
有些事我想和你谈谈
There's a little matter we need to talk about.
想要钱吗? 门都没有
Yeah. Money, right? Well, forget it.
不是要钱
No. Not money.
"运动年鉴"
Gray's Sports Almanac.
听见他说的话了 小姐们
You heard him, girls.
你们走吧
Party's over.
讲吧 你还知道些什么?
Start talking, kid. What else you know about that book?
首先告诉我你怎么拿到的
First, you tell me how you got it.
在何时、何地、如何拿到的
How, where and when.
好 你坐下来
All right. Take a seat.
坐下来!
Sit down!
时间是1955年11月12日
November 12, 1955. That was when.
1955年11月12日 那是我回来...
November 12, 1955. That was the date I went back...
那天正好是山谷镇 发生闪电暴风雨的日子
That was the date of the famous Hill Valley lightning storm.
你对历史知道得不少 很好
You know your history. Very good.
我永远忘不了那个星期六
I'll never forget that Saturday.
我从车行里把车开回来
I'd just picked my car up from the shop,
因为我去参加赛车
'cause I'd rolled it in a drag race a few days earlier.
你好像是撞进粪肥车里去
I thought you crashed into a manure truck.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know about that?
我爸爸告诉我的
My father told me about it.
你爸爸?
Your father?
在他死前
Before he died.
喔 对!
Yeah. Right.
我正在做我自己的事
So there I was, minding my own business.
一个拄着拐杖的疯老头跑过来
This crazy old codger with a cane shows up.
他说是我的远亲
He says he's my distant relative.
其实我们一点也不像
I don't see any resemblance.
他问我 你想发财吗
So he says, "How would you like to be rich?"
我说 当然
So I said, "Sure."
他就把这本书给我
So he lays this book on me.
他说这本书上有
He says this book will tell me the outcome
本世纪所有运动比赛的结果
of every sporting event till the end of the century.
我只要赌赢的那一方 就永远不会输
All I have to do is bet on the winner, and I'll never lose.
我问 你的目的是什么?
So I said, "What's the catch?"
他说 我没有目的 但你一定要保密
He says, "No catch. Just keep it a secret."
然后他就不见了
After that, he disappeared.
我一直没再看见他
I never saw him again.
他另外还告诉我一件事
Oh, and he told me one more thing.
他说 有一天一个疯狂科学家
He said, "Someday a crazy, wild-eyed scientist,
或是一个小孩可能会出现 问起这本书
"or a kid may show up asking about that book.
"如果真的发生了..."
"And if that ever happens..."
有趣 没想到会是你
Funny. I never thought it would be you.
贝夫 你忘了一件事
Yeah, well, Biff, you're forgetting one thing.
那是什么东西?
What the hell is that?
你死定了 混蛋!
You're dead, you little son of a bitch!
他在那里!
Hey, there he is!
等一下!
Hey, hey!
(屋顶)
有种就跳呀
Go ahead, kid. Jump.
自杀最好
A suicide will be nice and neat.
如果我不自杀呢?
What if I don't?
那就请你吃子弹
Lead poisoning.
你不怕警察吗?
What about the police, Biff?
他们会根据子弹找出手枪来
They're gonna match up the bullet with that gun.
警察归我管
Kid, I own the police.
况且他们至今仍找不到
Besides, they couldn't match up
杀你父亲的凶手
the bullet that killed your old man.
你是个狗养...
You son of a...
我想这就是因果报应
I suppose it's poetic justice.
两个麦佛莱被同一支枪杀死
Two McFlys with the same gun.
白痴
Idiot.
怎么搞的?
What the hell?
博士 门开得好!
Nice shot, Doc!
你一定不相信
You're not gonna believe this.
但我们得回到1955年
We gotta go back to 1955.
我不信
I don't believe it.
不错 是1955年11月12日
That's right, Doc. November 12, 1955.
那个老贝夫怎么会选那一天
Unbelievable that Old Biff could've chosen that particular date.
也许表示那一天
It could mean that that point in time
具有宇宙的重要性
inherently contains some sort of cosmic significance,
是时空暂时
almost as if it were the temporal junction point
汇聚点
for the entire space-time continuum.
或者那只是个巧合
On the other hand, it could just be an amazing coincidence.
(1885年1月1日 目的地时间)
该死 我得记得修这个
Damn! Got to fix that thing.
好 时间设定完成
All right. Time circuits on.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean, time circuits on?
我们现在就回去吗
Doc, we're not going back now.
对
Yep.
詹妮弗和爱因斯坦怎么办?
Doc, what about Jennifer? What about Einstein?
不能把他们留在这里
We can't just leave them here.
放心 假设我们成功了
Don't worry, Marty. Assuming we succeed in our mission,
这个被改变的1985年 就会变回原来的1985年
this alternate 1985 will be changed back into the real 1985,
詹妮弗和爱因斯坦 也就跟着转变
instantaneously transforming around Jennifer and Einie.
他们不会有事的
Jennifer and Einie will be fine,
而且会忘掉这里的一切
and they will have absolutely no memory of this horrible place.
博士
Doc.
如果不能成功呢?
What if we don't succeed?
一定要成功
We must succeed.
(里昂地产 您明日的家)
真奇怪 我怎么觉得好像昨天才来过
This is heavy, Doc. I mean, it's like I was just here yesterday.
你是昨天才来过
You were here yesterday, Marty. You were.
想不到吧?
Amazing, isn't it?
再过二十二分钟天就亮了
All right, sunrise should be in about 22 minutes.
你先进城 我来找小贝夫的行踪
You go into town. Track down Young Biff and tail him.
今天的某段时间 老贝夫会出现
Sometime today, Old Biff will show up
把书给小贝夫
to give Young Biff the almanac.
你不能干预
Above all you, must not interfere with that event.
让老贝夫以为他成功 这样他才会离开1955年
We must let Old Biff believe he's succeeded, so that he'll leave 1955
并把迪罗里安开到未来
and bring the DeLorean back to the future.
好
Right.
等老贝夫一走 只要有机会就把年鉴拿走
Once Old Biff is gone, grab the almanac any way that you can.
记住 我们的未来就靠这次行动
Remember, both of our futures depend on this.
你不用提醒我
You don't have to remind me of that, Doc.
这是望远镜和无线电话机 保持联系
Here's some binoculars and a walkie-talkie so we can keep in contact.
我在这里修机器
I'll stay here and try to repair the short in the time circuit.
这样就不怕有人偷车了
That way, we don't risk anyone else stealing the time machine,
也不会冒 碰到另一个自己的危险
and I won't risk accidentally running into my other self.
另一个自己?
Other self?
对 这里有两个我
Yes. There are now two of me here,
和两个你
and there are two of you here.
一个是1955年的布朗博士
The other me is the Dr. Emmett Brown from 1955,
他帮另一个你回到1985年
the younger me that helps the other you get back to 1985.
还记得电击钟塔吗?
Remember the lightning bolt at the clock tower?
那是今晚才发生
Yeah. That event doesn't happen until tonight,
所以千万小心不要碰到 另一个自己
so you must be very careful not to run into your other self.
你身上得带点钱
Let me give you some money.
(紧急现金)
必须准备好各种不同的钞票
I have to be prepared for all monetary possibilities.
去买件50年代的衣服
Get yourself some '50s clothes.
好的
Check, Doc.
别太引人注目
Something inconspicuous.
博士 这是马丁
Doc. Come in, Doc. This is Marty. Over.
知道了 你到了吗?
Roger, Marty. This is Doc. Are you there?
是的 我已到达这个地址
Yeah, Doc. I'm at the address.
只有一个添南家
It's the only Tannen in the book,
似乎不是贝夫的家
but I don't think this is Biff's house.
有个老太太住在这里
It looks like some old lady lives here.
贝夫
Biff! Yeah.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going, Biff?
奶奶 我去拿车
I'm going to get my car, Grandma.
你什么时候回来?
When are you coming back?
我要你按摩我的脚指头
My feet hurt, and I want you to rub my toes some more.
闭嘴 你这个老太婆
Shut up, you old bag.
把球还给我
Give us our ball back.
- 什么球? - 那个球!
- What ball? - That ball!
你们在说什么?
What ball are you talking about?
把球还给我们!
Give us our ball!
球?
What ball? Biff!
- 这是你们的球吗 - 是的!
- Is this your ball? - Yeah!
这是你们的球吗? 你们想要回去?
Is it your ball? You want it back?
是的
Yeah.
去拿呀
Go get it.
博士 那是贝夫的家 我正在跟踪他
Doc, it is Biff's house. I'm on him. Over.
嘿
Hey.
看起来不错
Looking good, Terry.
全修好了 像崭新的一样
Hey, Biff, she's all fixed up just like new,
我没办法发动它
but I couldn't get her started.
你装了特别的装置吧?
You got some kind of kill switch on this thing?
你得知道按哪里才行
No, you just gotta have the right touch.
除了我没人能发动这部车
Nobody can start this car but me.
一共三百零二元五毛七
Yeah, the bill comes to $302.57.
三百块钱?
300 bucks?
才几处小刮痕就要修三百元?
300 bucks for a couple of dents?
你开什么玩笑
No, hey, that's bullshit, Terry.
没有开玩笑
No, Biff, it was horse shit.
车里全是马粪
The whole car was full of it.
我还付约翰八十块把它弄走
We had to pay Old Man Jones 80 bucks to haul it away.
约翰可能把它卖了
Old Man Jones probably resold it, too.
你应该给我卖粪的钱
Now I ought to get something for that.
你要钱?
You want something for it?
打电话叫约翰给你
We'll go inside. You can call Old Man Jones.
如果他肯给你的话...
If he wants to give you a refund...
三百块!
It's 300 bucks, Terry.
让我找到那小鬼 一定把他脖子扭断
If I catch the guy that caused this, I'll break his neck.
粪肥 我记得了
The manure. I remember that.
四罐润滑油
Four cans of Valvoline is fair, Biff.
三百块只送四罐?
Four cans for a $300 job?
那是我的午餐钱
I couldn't even have lunch in the shop.
应该给我一箱润滑油
Makes me nauseous. I should get a case of oil
我才肯给你300块
out of you for a 300 buck job. You've been inside.
你的大便车比厕所还难闻
It smells worse than the bathroom at a gas station.
你又抢劫了我 对!
You robbed me again, Terry. Yeah, yeah.
这种味道永远不会消失
The smell's never gonna go away, Biff.
永远不会消失
Never gonna go away.
这是最后一次帮你 谢啦
Last time I do you a favor. Last time. Thanks a lot.
让我看看
Let me see.
洛莲 太美了
It's perfect, Lorraine.
看看!
Oh, look at it!
你一定会很漂亮!
You're going to look so good!
你看起来会像...
You're going to look...
你们在讲什么?
Well, lookey what we have here.
衣服真漂亮
Hey, nice dress, Lorraine.
但我觉得 你什么都不穿会更好看
Although, I think you'd look better wearing nothing at all.
你为什么不去跳海?
Biff, why don't you take a long walk off a short pier?
听着 洛莲
Hey, listen, Lorraine.
今晚学校有舞会
There's that dance at school tonight, right.
我的车修好了
Now that my car's all fixed,
所以你有机会
I figure I'd cut you a break
很荣幸
and give you the honor of going
和最英俊的我一起去参加
with the best-looking guy in school.
我很忙
Yeah, well, I'm busy.
- 忙什么? - 忙着洗头发
- Yeah, doing what? - Washing my hair.
那和战舰装纱门一样好笑
That's about as funny as a screen door on a battleship.
笨蛋 是潜艇装纱门
Screen door on a submarine, you dork.
已经有人邀请我了
Look, Biff, somebody already asked me to the dance.
谁? 那个猪头乔治吗?
Who? That bug George McFly?
我要和卡尔文克莱一起去
I'm going with Calvin Klein, okay?
卡尔文克莱? 不行
Calvin Klein? No, it's not okay.
你要和我一起去 懂吗?
You're going with me, understand?
把你的爪子拿开!
Get your cooties off me!
什么时候你才能想清楚?
When are you gonna get it through your thick skull, Lorraine?
你是我的女孩
You're my girl.
就算你有一百万
Biff Tannen, I wouldn't be your girl
我也不要你!
even if you had a million dollars!
你会的! 你我一定会在一起
Yes, you will! It's you and me, Lorraine.
小心点!
Watch it!
这是命中注定的
It's meant to be.
总有一天我会娶你
I'm going to marry you someday, Lorraine.
你会变成我太太!
Someday you'll be my wife!
你对女人永远有一套
You always did have a way with women.
老家伙 滚出我的车
Get the hell out of my car, old man.
你想娶她吗?
You want to marry that girl, Biff?
我能帮你
I can help make it happen.
你是谁 寂寞芳心俱乐部吗?
Oh, yeah? Who are you, Miss Lonely-Hearts?
笨蛋 上车
Just get in the car, butthead.
你叫谁笨蛋 笨蛋
Who are you calling butthead, butthead?
你怎么弄的?
How do you know how to do that?
除了我没人会发动我的车
Nobody can start this car but me.
快上车 今天算你走运
Just get in the car, Tannen. Today's your lucky day.
老家伙 你小心开
Hey! Hey! Hey, watch where you're driving, old man.
刮到它 我就杀了你
If you dent this car, I'll kill you.
天呀!
God
我才花了三百块
This cost me 300 bucks!
你别再念了 行不行?
Would you shut up about the car?
你怎么知道我住哪里?
Hey, and another thing. How do you know where I live?
算我们有亲戚关系吧
Let's just say we're related, Biff.
正因为如此 我有个礼物给你
And that being the case, I got a little present for you.
会让你发大财
Something that'll make you rich.
你想发财 对不对?
You want to be rich, don't you?
那当然 老迷糊
Oh, yeah. Sure. Right. That's rich.
难道你能让我发财吗?
You're going to make me rich?
看到这本书吗 这本书会告诉你未来
You see this book? This book tells the future.
它告诉你 本世纪所有
Tells the results of every major sports event
运动比赛的结果
till the end of the century.
不管是足球、棒球 赛马、拳击赛
Football, baseball, horse races, boxing.
里面的资料值千百万 我现在把它给你
The information in here is worth millions, and I'm giving it to you.
非常谢谢你
Well, that's very nice. Thank you very much.
你说完了吧 那就请你离去之
Now, why don't you make like a tree and get out of here?
笨蛋 不是离去之 是离去兮
It's leave, you idiot. Make like a tree and leave.
你咬文嚼字像个大白痴
You sound like a damn fool when you say it wrong.
好 你走! 把书也带走
All right, then, leave and take your book with you.
你怎么还是没想通? 用这本书你可以发大财
Don't you get it? You could make a fortune with this book.
让我证明给你看
Let me show you.
加州大学落后 比数是17比16
UCLA trails 17-16.
这场比赛只剩下18秒钟
It's 4th and 11 with only 18 seconds left of this game.
看来加州大学输定了
I'd say it's all over for UCLA.
我和你赌加州大学 以19比17获胜
Bet you a million bucks UCLA wins it 19-17.
你是不是聋了
What are you, deaf, old man?
比赛已经结束 你输了
He just said it was over. You lost.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
现在踢球
Here comes Decker with the kick.
看起来很不错
It's up. It looks good, folks!
看起来很不错 踢进球门! 加州大学队 以19比17获胜
It looks very good. Field goal! UCLA wins 19-17.
所有的观众都疯狂了...
Listen to that Coliseum crowd go wild. Jim Decker...
好 到底是怎么回事?
All right, pops. What's the gag?
你怎么会知道比数?
How did you know what the score was gonna be?
告诉你 全在这本书里
I told you. It's in this book.
你只要赌赢的那一方 就永远不会输
All you gotta do is bet on the winner, and you'll never lose.
好吧 我会看一看
All right. I'll take a look at it.
你这个笨蛋!
You damn fool!
永远...永远不能把书随便放
Never, never leave this book laying around.
你难道没有保险箱? 对 你没有
Don't you have a safe? No, you don't have a safe.
去买个保险箱 把它锁在里面
Get a safe. Keep it locked up.
在那之前 永远放在你身上
And until then, keep it on you like this.
你干嘛?
Hey, what are you doing?
不能对任何人提起
And don't tell anybody about it, either.
还有一件事
And there's one more thing.
有一天一个孩子 或是一个疯老头
One day, a kid or a crazy, wild-eyed old man
说他自己是科学家
who claims to be a scientist
会来这里问...
is going to come around asking about this...
如果发生了这件事...
If that ever happens...
我出不去了 博士
I'm trapped. Doc.
博士 请回答
Doc, come in, Doc.
- 情况如何? - 贝夫走了
- Marty, what's the report? - Biff's gone.
他拿到书
He's got the book.
老人也走了 我被锁在贝夫的车房里
The old man's gone, too. I'm locked in Biff's garage.
你开迪罗里安
You gotta fly the DeLorean over here
来这里救我
and get me the hell out of here.
地址是梅森街1809号
The address is 1809 Mason Street.
白天不能开这部车
I can't take the DeLorean out in the daylight,
别担心 我会想办法过去的
but don't worry, Marty. Somehow I'll get over there.
博士 等一下...
Doc, wait a minute. Doc. Hey, Doc. Doc.
真倒霉
Perfect.
贝夫 你到哪里去?
Biff,where are you going now?
奶奶 不是告诉你我要去参加舞会
I told you, Grandma. I'm going to the dance.
- 几点回家? - 舞会?
- When you coming home? - The dance.
我想回来时就会回来
I'll get home when I get home.
别忘了关车库的灯
Don't forget to turn off the garage light.
马丁 马丁!
Marty. Marty!
马丁
Marty.
马丁 马丁 糟糕!
Marty, Marty. Damn!
马丁到哪儿去了呢?
Where is that kid?
∮ 爸爸爱曼波 ∮
∮ Father loves Mambo ∮
∮ 妈妈爱曼波... ∮
∮ Mother loves Mambo... ∮
博士 请回答
Doc. Doc, come in.
Come in, Doc.
马丁 请说
Marty! Marty, come in.
博士
Doc.
马丁
Marty.
糟糕...
Oh, my...
我的天
Great Scott.
天啊
Oh, my God.
博士 请回答
Doc, Doc, come in.
马丁 怎么回事?
Marty, what happened to you?
你怎么没在贝夫家
I went to Biff's house, and you weren't there.
我们错过了
You must have just missed me.
我在贝夫车里
I'm in the back of Biff's car.
正在往舞会的方向前进
He's on his way to the Enchantment Under the Sea dance.
可能要取消这个计划
Marty, listen, we may have to abort this entire plan.
太危险了
It's getting much too dangerous.
书就在车子的仪表板上
Don't worry. The book is on Biff's dashboard.
我会拿到的
I'll grab it as soon as we get to the school.
马丁 你千万要小心
Marty, you must be extremely careful
别撞上另一个自己
not to run into your other self.
- 另一个自己? - 对!
- My other self? - Yes.
因为你妈妈和你 也去参加同一个舞会
Remember, your mother is at that exact same dance with you. Yeah.
对 太严重了
Right. This could get heavy, Doc.
严重 严重
Heavy, heavy.
不管发生什么事 都不能让另一个自己看到你!
Marty, whatever happens, you must not let your other self see you!
否则后果不堪设想
The consequences could be disastrous.
先生 帮个忙
Excuse me, sir.
就是戴帽子的那位
Yes, you with the hat.
谁 我吗?
Who, me?
是的
Yes.
拜托把工具箱里 八分之五的板手递给我
Be a pal and hand me a five-eighths inch wrench out of that toolbox.
八分之五的板手?
Five-eighths?
应该是四分之三吧?
Don't you mean three-quarters?
你说对了
Why, you're right.
看来你像是在做某种天气测试
I presume you're conducting some sort of weather experiment.
没错 你怎么知道的?
That's right. How did you know that?
我在这方面有点经验
I happen to have had a little experience in this area.
我希望今晚能有闪电出现
Yes, well, I'm hoping to see some lightning tonight.
尽管气象员说不会有雨
Although, the weatherman says there's not gonna be any rain.
放心 会有很多的雨
There's going to be plenty of rain, all right.
风 打雷、闪电
Wind, thunder, lightning.
将是个很大的暴风雨
It's gonna be one hell of a storm.
谢谢你 很高兴和你聊天
Well, thanks. Nice talking to you.
说不定将来会再见面
Maybe we'll bump into each other some time again in the future.
也许是过去
Or in the past.
博士 请回答
Doc, Doc! Come in!
(海洋魅力舞会)
(美女图鉴)
乔伊 那个猪头卡尔文克莱在哪儿?
Where's that punk Calvin Klein, anyway?
我怎么会知道
How am I supposed to know, Biff?
我又不是他的秘书
I ain't his secretary.
去找他 他害我花了三百块
Well, go find him. He caused 300 bucks damage to my car,
我一定要赏他一顿饱拳!
and I owe him a knuckle sandwich. Get going!
- 快去! 这给你 - 谢谢
- Drink up, Biff. - Yeah, thanks.
你不来吗?
Ain't you coming?
我要看书
I'm reading.
很好 贝夫
Well, well, well, Mr. Tannen.
很高兴看到你在这里
How nice to see you here.
史特兰老师 很高兴见到你
Why, Mr. Strickland, it's nice to see you, sir.
我好像闻到酒味
Is that liquor I smell, Tannen?
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
我不知酒为何物
I don't know what liquor smells like,
因为我太年轻不能喝酒
'cause I'm too young to drink it.
是吗
I see.
你在看什么?
And what have we here?
运动年鉴 有趣的主题 是家庭作业吗?
Sports statistics, interesting subject. Homework, Tannen?
不是 我又不在家里 怎么会是家庭作业
No, it ain't homework, 'cause I ain't at home.
你的态度非常有问题
You've got a real attitude problem.
知道吗? 走着瞧
You know that, Tannen? Just watch it.
总有一天
Because one day, I'll have you
我要好好处罚你
right where I want you in detention.
懒鬼!
Slacker!
天啊 你还抽烟?
Jesus, you smoke, too?
你讲话跟我妈一样
Marty, you're beginning to sound just like my mother.
好吧
Yeah, right.
等我有小孩 我会让他们做他们想做的事
When I have kids, I'm going to let them do anything they want.
任何事
Anything at all.
真该让她写契约书
Yeah, I'd like to have that in writing.
我也是这么觉得
Yeah, me, too.
马丁 你干嘛这么紧张?
Marty, why are you so nervous?
(训导处)
拿到了!
Yes!
不!
No!
怎么会是"美女图鉴"
"Oh Lo Lo?"
博士?
Doc! Doc!
混蛋 把你的脏手拿开...
Hey, you.
博士 请回答!
Doc, come in!
马丁 怎么样?
Marty, what's up?
我搞砸了
Doc! I'm in trouble. I blew it.
书在哪里?
Where's the book?
在贝夫那里
Biff must still have it with him.
我只拿到封页
All I got is the damn cover.
贝夫在哪里?
And where's Biff?
这是你自找的 我不知道
You're asking for it. I don't know.
你不知道?
Don't you have any idea where he is?
他现在可能在任何地方
No! I mean, he could be anywhere by now.
大家的未来都决定在
Marty, the entire future depends on you
你能不能拿到那本书!
finding Biff and getting that book back!
我知道 我只是...
I know. I just don't know where...
贝夫 住手!
Stop it!
住手 他的手会断的
Stop it, Biff. You'll break his arm. Stop it!
当然!
Of course!
我得走了 还有一个机会!
I gotta go. I got one chance!
我老爸将要揍贝夫了!
My old man is about to deck Biff!
好!
Yes!
好像进入幻境一样
Talk about deja vu.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
好了 大家让一让
Okay, everybody, let's back up now.
退后一点
Let's back up. Let's everybody just back up
给他一点空间
and give him a little bit of room, okay.
给他一点空气
A little bit of air.
没问题 我会心肺复苏术
It's okay. I know CPR. I know CPR.
嘿
Hey.
什么是心肺复苏术?
What's CPR?
是你!
You!
他没事
He's fine.
你是不是拿了他的皮夹?
Hey, did you just take his wallet?
他把那家伙的皮夹拿走
He just took that guy's wallet.
博士 我拿到了
Doc, success. I got it.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.
干的好 马丁
Great, Marty.
我把熔解器装上
As soon as I reload the fusion generator,
我们在体育馆屋顶见
I'll meet you on the roof of the high school gym.
屋顶见 知道了
On the roof. 10-4.
嘿 是他!
Hey, it's him!
他想伪装逃跑
Hey, he's in disguise.
那是什么?
Guys, what's that?
去抓他!
Come on! Let's get him!
该死!
Damn!
(1885年1月1日 目的地时间)
∮ 凡间天使 ∮
∮ Earth angel ∮
∮ 请属于我 ∮
∮ Please be mine ∮
∮ 我亲爱的 ∮
∮ My darling dear ∮
∮ 永远爱你 ∮
∮ Love you for all time ∮
∮ 我是傻瓜 ∮
∮ I'm just a fool ∮
∮ 爱上你的 ∮
∮ A fool in love ∮
∮ 傻瓜 ∮
∮ with you
好 我们再唱一首
All right! Let's do another one.
他到哪里去了? 不是才进来嘛!
Where did he go? He just came in here!
该来一首特别的
Something that really cooks.
你们看! 他怎么会到台上去了
Look! How did he get up on stage?
等他下台就去抓他
I don't know, but when he gets down, we're gonna nail him.
衣服怎么会换得这么快
How the hell did he change his clothes so fast?
在我们那边是老歌
All right, it's an oldie where I come from.
这是一首即兴蓝调
All right, guys, listen, this is a blues riff in B.
注意我的节拍 尽量跟上
Watch me for the changes, and try and keep up, okay?
博士 请回答!
Doc. Doc, come in!
马丁 请说
Marty, come in.
贝夫的同党追进体育馆 他们要抓我
Listen, Biff's guys chased me into the gym, and they're going to jump me.
那就快离开那里
Then get out of there!
不 是另一个我
No, Doc, not me. The other me.
就是那个在舞台上演奏的我
The one that's up on stage playing Johnny B. Goode.
我的天! 那他
Great Scott! Your other self will miss
会错失钟楼闪电
the lightning bolt at the clock tower,
而你会回不去 这是大灾难!
you won't get back to the future, and we'll have a major paradox!
等等 什么灾难?
Wait, wait, wait. A paradox?
是会毁灭宇宙的灾难吗?
You mean one of those things that can destroy the universe?
你要设法阻止那些人
Precisely. Marty, you have to stop those guys at all costs,
同时不能碰上另一个你 或是你的父母
but without being seen by your other self or your parents.
知道了
10-4.
怎么搞的?
What the hell?
- 他到哪里去了? - 谁?
- Where is he? - Who?
- 卡尔文克莱 - 谁?
- Calvin Klein. - Who?
戴帽子的家伙 他在哪?
The guy with the hat, where is he?
他往那边去了
Oh. He went that way.
我好像看到他拿了你的皮夹 我好像看到他拿了你的皮夹
I think he took your wallet. I think he took his wallet.
走 强尼 走 走
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
强尼毕谷
Johnny B. Goode
走 走
Go, go
走 强尼 走 走
Go, Johnny, go, go
走 强尼 走 走 走
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
走 强尼 走 走
Go, Johnny, go, go
走 强尼 走 走 走
Go, Johnny, go, go, go
强尼毕谷
Johnny B. Goode
你们大概还没办法 接受这样的音乐
I guess you guys aren't ready for that yet.
但是你们的小孩会喜欢的
But your kids are going to love it.
博士 成功了 没事了
Hey, Doc, success. Everything's cool.
我在一分钟内 会降落在屋顶上
Great. I'll be landing at the school roof in about one minute.
我在那里等你
I'll be there.
洛莲
Lorraine.
马丁 那首歌满特别的
Marty, that was very interesting music.
我希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind,
乔治说要送我回家
but George asked if he could take me home.
好 我就知道你们会合得来
Great. Lorraine, I had a feeling about you two.
我也这么觉得
I have a feeling, too.
喂 笨蛋!
Hey, butthead!
你以为那种伪装能骗得了我?
You think that stupid disguise would get by me?
咱们来分个胜负 现在 你和我
Let's have it out. You and me, right now.
不用了
No, thanks.
怎么啦?
What's the matter?
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
原来你是个胆小鬼
Are you chicken?
说对了 你是个胆小鬼
That's it, isn't it? Nothing but a little chicken.
没人叫我胆小鬼
Nobody calls me chicken.
怎么...
What the hell?
你居然偷我东西?
You steal my stuff?
这一脚是为我车子踢的!
And this one's for my car!
博士!
Doc!
博士 我搞砸了
Doc! I blew it.
贝夫抓到我 并把书拿走了
Biff nailed me. He took the book.
他开车走了
He drove away with it in his car.
是我的错 我应该早点来
It's my fault, Doc. I should have got out of there sooner.
不管了 他往哪儿去?
No time for that now. Which way did he go?
向东 朝隧道开去了
East towards the River Road Tunnel.
快上车!
Get in!
找到了!
Yes!
博士 他就在那里!
There he is, Doc!
降落在他车上 把车弄瘫掉
Let's land on him. We'll cripple his car.
我们是迪罗里安 太轻了
Marty, he's in a '46 Ford. We're a DeLorean.
反而会被他拆散
He'd rip through us like we were tin foil.
- 那我们该怎么做? - 我有办法
- So what do we do? - I have a plan.
重复今晚的气象报告
Repeating tonight's earlier weather bulletin,
一场大雷雨 正朝山谷镇方向进行
a severe thunderstorm is heading for Hill Valley.
本电台服务所有山谷郡地区
Serving Hill Valley and all of Hill County,
您现在正收听KKHV电台 山谷之声
you're tuned to KKHV, the voice of Hill Valley.
至于社区日程表
Turning to community calendar,
山谷镇妇女俱乐部蛋糕拍卖会
the Hill Valley Women's Club bake sale
将于明天下午两点到五点举行
will be held tomorrow afternoon
地点是在 森林路的社区活动中心
from 2:00 to 5:00 at the community center on Forest Road.
至于运动迷
For you sports fans out there,
今天的大学足球赛真是高潮起伏
there was a lot of action today in college football.
这是前十名的资料
Here's what happened to the top 10.
加州大学 以19比17胜华盛顿大学
UCLA narrowly defeated Washington 19-17.
密歇根州大学 以42比14胜明尼苏达
Michigan State crushed Minnesota 42-14.
俄亥俄州大学 以20比10胜爱荷华
Ohio State beat lowa 20-10.
密歇根大胜印第安纳
Michigan blanked Indiana 30-0.
糟糕!
Shit.
圣母院赢北卡罗来纳 27比7
It was Notre Dame over North Carolina, 27-7.
他妈的!
Son of a bitch.
俄克拉荷马 大胜爱荷华州大学
Oklahoma ripped lowa State 52-0.
西弗吉尼亚 以26比7输给匹兹堡
West Virginia lost to Pittsburgh 26-7.
德州农工大学 以20比10赢莱斯队
Texas A&M over Rice 20-10.
马里兰 以25比12胜克雷蒙森
Maryland defeated Clemson 25-12,
德州基督大学 以47比20胜德州大学
and it was Texas Christian over Texas 47-20.
重复今晚的气象报告 一场大雷雨...
Repeating tonight's earlier weather bulletin, a severe...
又是你? 把那本书给我
You again? Give me that book.
放手!
Let it go!
离我的车远一点!
Let go of the car!
(前方有隧道)
他应该学到教训了
That'll teach him.
博士 快走!
Go, Doc!
马丁 抓紧!
Hold on, Marty!
该死!
Shit!
活该!
Yes!
粪肥! 我恨粪肥!
Manure! I hate manure!
博士 一切都好吧
Doc, is everything all right? Over.
这不是飞行的好天气
10-4, Marty, but it's pretty miserable flying weather.
降落时会遇到很多乱流
Much too turbulent to make a landing from this direction.
我必须从南方进来
I'll have to circle around and make a long approach from the south.
你拿到书了吗?
Have you got the book?
拿到了 就在我手中!
In my hand, Doc! I got it in my hand!
烧掉它!
Burn it!
好!
Check!
(贝夫的家)
(极乐天堂)
(汽车保养)
(乔治麦佛莱被谋杀  本地作家被枪杀致死)
(乔治麦佛莱的荣耀  本地作家得奖)
博士 报纸变了
Doc! Doc! That newspaper changed.
我爸爸没死!
Doc, my father's alive!
那表示一切回复正常 对不对?
That means everything's back to normal, right?
(艾米布朗被判决  疯子发明家被判神精错乱)
(艾米布朗接受表扬  本地发明家获奖)
任务完成
Mission accomplished.
这表示詹妮弗和爱因斯坦也都没事 对不对?
That means Jennifer's okay and Einie's okay, right?
没错 影响已在逐渐扩大
That's right, Marty. It's the ripple effect.
未来已经正常了 我们回去吧
The future is back, so let's go home.
对 赶快把我接走 好回到...
Right. Let's get our asses back to the...
博士 你没事吧?
Doc, Doc, are you okay?
真惊险 我几乎买了那个农场
That was a close one, Marty. I almost bought the farm.
小心点 别让闪电击到
Well, be careful. You don't want to get struck by lightning.
博士
Doc.
博士?
Doc?
博士 请回答
Doc, come in, Doc.
你听得到吗?
Doc, do you read me?
你听得到吗 请回答
Do you read me, Doc? Come in. Doc.
天呐!
Oh, no.
他死了
He's gone.
博士死了
The doc's gone.
麦佛莱先生!
Mr. McFly!
啊?
Huh?
你的名字是马丁麦佛莱吗?
Is your name Marty McFly?
是的
Yeah.
我有东西要交给你
I've got something for you.
一封信
A letter.
一封给我的信?
A letter for me?
怎么可能
That's impossible.
你是谁?
Who the hell are you?
西部联合银行
Western Union.
我们公司的人
Actually, a bunch of us at the office were kind of hoping
希望你能点醒我们
maybe you could shed some light on the subject.
我们持有这封信已有七十年
See, we've had that envelope in our possession for the past 70 years.
上面有着非常清楚的指示
It was given to us with the explicit instructions
要我们交给像你这样的年青人
that it be delivered to a young man with your description
他的名字是马丁 就在1955年11月12日
answering to the name of Marty at this exact location
这个时间、这个地点
at this exact minute, November 12, 1955.
我们甚至下注赌
We have a little bet going as to whether
马丁会不会出现
this Marty would actually be here.
看来我输了
Looks like I lost.
你说是七十年前?
Did you say 70 years?
正确的时间是 七十年两个月又十二天
Yeah, 70 years, 2 months, 12 days to be exact.
请在第六行签名
Here sign on line 6, please.
这是笔
Here you are.
(你的朋友布朗博士)
这是博士寄来的!
It's from the doc!
"亲爱的马丁 如果我的计算无误
"Dear Marty, if my calculations are correct,
在你看到迪罗里安 被闪电击中后
you will receive this letter immediately after
你会马上看到这封信
you saw the DeLorean struck by lightning.
首先你放心 我活得很好
First, let me assure you that I'm alive and well.
过去八个月中 我在1885年代活的很愉快
I've been living happily these past eight months in the year 1885.
闪电使我进入... 1885年!
The lightning bolt...1885!
1885年的9月"
September, 1885."
喂 等等 这到底是怎么回事?
Wait, wait, kid! Wait a minute. What's this all about?
他还活着 博士还活着!
He's alive! The doc's alive!
他在老西部 但仍活着
He's in the Old West, but he's alive.
你没事吧?
Yeah, but, kid, you all right?
需要帮忙吗?
Do you need any help?
只有一个人能帮我
There's only one man who can help me.
博士! 博士! 博士!
Doc! Doc! Doc!
- 博士! 博士! - 什么?
- Doc! Doc! - What?
博士 别怕 是我马丁
Okay, relax, Doc. It's me. It's me! It's Marty.
不可能! 我才把你送回未来
No, it can't be. I just sent you back to the future.
我知道
Yeah. No, I know. You did send me
但我又回来了
back to the future, but I'm back.
我又从未来回来了
I'm back from the future.
我的天!
Great Scott!
博士 博士 博士
Doc! Doc. Doc.
你怎么啦? 博士
Fantastic.
(未完待续)
(山谷镇)
嘿 麦佛莱
Hey, McFly.
添南 看枪!
Just try it, Tannen!
来呀 小矮子 跳舞呀!
Come on, runt! You can dance better than that!
《回到未来3》